Okay, so let's discuss some of the common
reasons why people fail the exam the first
time, and really so that you don't fall
into any of these categories.
Now, one of the main reasons
why people fail the exam
the first time is they haven't
done enough studying.
Just like any exam you've ever taken,
you need the time to study for this exam.
It amazes me how many
students are going into
the exam and they're just
going in underprepared.
I asked students, why did he fail?
What was your study tactic?
And they said, oh, I just memorized the
formula sheet and the process grid.
That's all he did?
Well, of course he's going to fail if
that's all you did.
Remember, what is the exam testing you?
It is testing your knowledge and
understanding of PMI's principles.
It's testing your knowledge and
understanding of PMI's standards.
Remember, the PMP exam is not test.
how well you manage
projects in your organization,
projects in your industry.
So it doesn't matter how many years of
experience you have, that's not
necessarily going to make you pass the PMP
exam.
And again, I've had students
in my classes that come in and
say, oh, I've got 20 years of
experience of project management.
Why do I need to study?
Well, you need to study because you've got
20 years of experience in your industry in
your organization, you don't have 20 years
of experience of understanding PMI
standards or PMI's principles,
right?
That's why you need to study.
It's testing your knowledge and
understanding of PMI standards.
That's what you need to learn.
And this moves over, or this takes me to
the next bullet point here, not taking
enough practice questions, not taking
enough practice exams.
Your key to studying is
going through practice exams,
questions, Question after
question after question.
Because there's a lot of curveball that
PMI throw at you on the exam.
They'll give you irrelevant information.
It's all scenario question,
but sometimes the
entire scenario is
irrelevant to the question.
Or they'll give you irrelevant information
within the scenario.
They'll mismatch terminology.
There'll also be some key words in there.
You need to learn to pick out keywords and
phrases.
One key word could change.
the context of the question.
So you need to understand exam strategy,
exam technique.
Learning the materials is just one part.
Exam technique is the other part of
passing the exam.
And the only way of learning
exam technique, right, exam
strategy is by going through
question after question.
Now, during these video
classes, right, we have
videos on exam strategy
and exam technique.
and what kind of things to look out for on
the PMP exam.
But you need to practice those.
And the only way of practicing is by going
through questions,
questions and practice exams.
I mean, it is literally a case of practice
makes perfect.
Now, these next two bullet points are two
other common reasons
why people fail the exam.
Either they've taken the exam too early or
they've taken it too,
or they left it too late.
you need to take the exam when you're
ready to take the exam and ready right by
ready what I mean is you've studied enough
you've gone through enough practice exams
and practice questions right and materials
are still fresh in your mind you can still
think in terms of PMI
standards you can still think like
PMI you can still think in
terms of PMI's principles Right.
And everybody's different.
So I mean, I mean, I can't tell you
exactly, you know, how many hours of
studying you should be
doing or, you know, how
many days or weeks after
you've watched the videos.
There's many, many different variables,
right?
Especially when it's asynchronous class
like this.
But what I will tell you is this.
Don't just take the exam immediately after
watching the videos.
Don't just watch the videos and then go
take the exam.
Plus at the same time, don't wait several
months.
either and you need just have a proper
study plan and it's no point in just
watching a video here and there and then
you know waiting a few weeks watching
another video that's not going to work
either you need to have a proper study
plan and have a study plan right make sure
that you know you're going to do this
topic on this day this topic on this day
this topic on this day make sure you're
going through practice quizzes and
practice exams and then again after you've
watch all the videos, make sure you're
taking plenty of questions.
Take the exam when you're ready.
When you're ready, when you
had enough time to go through
practice exams and the materials
are still fresh in your mind.
Don't take it too early, don't leave it
too late.
Now here's another
very, very common reason
why people fail the exam the first time.
You cannot get past your own experiences.
have to understand.
These are PMI's standards.
These are PMI's principles.
Every industry manages projects
differently.
There's no right or wrong way of managing
a project, right?
Different industries manage projects
differently.
And plus, you're in a predictive environment
or you're in an agile environment.
Project management is very, very different
in both environments.
And half the exam is predictive.
Half the exam is agile.
So you need to be able to think in both
terms.
So you need to be able
to have an open mind and
understand every industry
manages projects differently.
This is PMI's industry.
This is PMI's principles.
Or these are PMI's principles that you're
learning.
So you have to answer the exam based on
PMI's principles.
Everything you've learned about project
management.
Put at the back of your mind.
Unlearn everything you've learnt and start
thinking in terms of PMI standards now.
So when you're answering the exam
question, when you're looking at the
option choices, don't jump to
the option choice that sounds
reasonable based on what you
would do in your organisation.
You need to take a step
back and think in terms
of, is this in line with PMI's principles?
Now, one of the other reasons why people
actually fail is just be able.
nervous.
This is just an exam.
Don't go into the exam nervous.
If you've done enough
studying, then there's
no reason why you shouldn't pass the exam.
And I will tell you right now,
almost everybody, not everyone,
but almost everyone, always feels like
they've gone into the exam underprepared.
Everybody feels that way.
If I even felt that way when I was taking
my exam.
I felt I need to do more studying.
I didn't feel like I was
prepared and everybody,
I can tell you, almost
everyone feels that way.
They go into the exam and they
think they haven't done enough
studying or they feel that
they're underprepared, right?
So regardless of how much studying,
you know, people have done.
So I will just say this,
you know, don't be nervous
when you go into the, when
you take the exam, right?
I mean, I have seen students where,
prepared really well.
There's no reason why
they shouldn't fail the
exam, but they just
got really nervous, right?
And they started, you know, spending a lot
of time on one question and not enough
time on other questions and they ended up
sometimes not even finishing the exam.
Don't let that happen to you, right?
It's just an exam after all, right?
All you can do is try your best.
That's all.
Okay, so go in there as relaxed as you
can.